

Michael Horvath

michaelhor vath 87@gmail.com



949 - 409 - 5713



www.michaelhorvathdataguy.com

About me -

Originally from Kansas, Michael has lived in eight states and three countries. Michael enjoys climbing, running, playing guitar and anything that gets him outside. He's been writing software for about seven years now, but he's been exploring since the day he could walk – perhaps even earlier.

Skill

Linux

APIs

Python

Flask

Scalability

Figuring-it-out

SRE

Cloud Services (AWS, Azure)

Design and Architecture

 ${\bf Design\text{-}and\text{-}Architecture}$

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

motto

Continual growth is key to enjoyment of life; challenge begets growth.

Software = Poetry + Math

education

2006-2011 B.A. cum laude

University of Kansas

Statistics and Research Methods

awa<mark>rds</mark>

1997-2001 Five Time Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania

2005 Science Olympiad State Champion, Chemistry

2006 CalTech Signature Award, Excellence in Science and Mathematics

2016 Heart and Soul Award, Lawrence Ultimate Frisbee League

work history

02/22-01/23 Software Engineer

Maxar Technologies

- Microservices development in enterprise asynchronous GIS system.

- AWS lambda functions, cloud deployment, and site-reliability engineering via infrastructure-as-code (IaC).

12/20-02/22 Senior Software Engineer

Fluxergy

- Led Data and Algorithms team, improving accuracy and performance of new algorithms.

- Architected DataHub for cross-departmental use and improved efficiency.

- Collaborated with Product team in strategy matters and actively researched new technologies to improve team productivity.

- Mentored junior engineers and participated in design and code reviews.

06/18-12/20 Software Engineer

Fluxergy

- Fullstack development, from requirements to cloud deployment.

- Embedded systems algorithm development for software on medical device.

- Designed and developed data warehousing and extraction systems.

05/17-06/18 Machine Learning Engineer

Embrace Healthwear

- Signal processing, feature selection, data vectorization, model selection for high-frequency ML classification problems.

2012 - 2016 Carpenter

Various Construction

- Swinging a hammer and singing Fleet Foxes.

2015 - 2022 Personal Projects

- Neural net generator for exploring automated generation, tuning and lifecycle of machine learning models in Elixir.

- High frequency trading algorithm development and back-testing.

skills

Technical

Python, Django, Flask, Sanic, PHP, MySQL, Docker, LaTex, docker-compose, Git, C++, make, CLion, Database design, Elasticsearch and Kibana, PowerBI, Javascript/HTML/CSS, CI/CD, Infrastructure as code, Google, Microsoft Office, Excel, Typescript, Statistics, Structural Equation Modeling, ANOVA, MANOVA, Regression, Multiple Regression, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, PyTorch, Pandas, Numpy, SciPy, SVM, Decision Trees, Docker, Azure, AWS, Lambda functions, SAAS, Microservices, Anomoly Detection

General

Program evaluation, technical liaison, presentation and public speaking, business intelligence, requirements gathering, data visualization, data wrangling, project management, Kanban, Jira, DevOps.